<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meshes and Textures on Workbook 9: Meshes and Textures</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meshes and Textures on Workbook 9: Meshes and Textures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:16:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meshes: What you need to know</title>
      <link>/docs/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:16:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/1/</guid>
      <description>We discussed meshes in class. Here are the things you need to know.
Mesh Concepts The main concepts you need to know:
 What is a mesh (as a collection of triangles) Why we avoid &amp;ldquo;Triangle Soup&amp;rdquo; What is a good mesh  avoiding T-Junctions good triangles consistent orientations   Indexing vertices for efficiency Vertex and Face Properties The need for Vertex Sharing The need for fancy representations  You don&amp;rsquo;t need to know a fancy representation (like Winged-Edge) but you should have a sense why they are important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 1: Meshes</title>
      <link>/docs/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:16:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/2/</guid>
      <description>In the world below (files 2-1.html and 2-1.js) make three objects and place them into the world so all can be seen.
They can be anything. They just must have 3 or more triangles, and you have to make each one from a Geometry and put them into the 559 Framework. You can even use the objects from later parts of the assignments (pages 6 and 7) if they fullfill the requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texture Basics</title>
      <link>/docs/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:16:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/3/</guid>
      <description>This page are some notes about texturing. The notes are meant to remind you about what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned in class and point you towards resources to learn more from. This is not a texture tutorial.
The Big Picture Texturing is a way to add details to a scene without making the geometry more complex. Effectively, it provides a way to make a decision about appearance for every pixel on the screen - without having to make triangles that are pixel-sized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textures in THREE</title>
      <link>/docs/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:16:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/4/</guid>
      <description>Using textures is notoriously tricky because there are a lot of steps involved. Fortunately, THREE makes it remarkably easy - it takes care of all of the little details, allowing you to focus on the big parts (setting coordinates, defining the texture image).
If you want a sense of how much had to happen to get a cube with texture on it, have a look at the 2015 example! And this doesn&amp;rsquo;t do any lighting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dice and Dominos (Exercise 2 and 3)</title>
      <link>/docs/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/5/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve made lots of boxes in THREE. Now we&amp;rsquo;ll turn a box into a die (one of a set of dice) and into a domino. All this means is we take a white box and put some dots on the side. For dice, we put a different number of dots on each side. For a domino, we put to sets of dots on the top.
We&amp;rsquo;ve provided you with a simple texture with all 6 patterns of dots (1-6) in the file images/dice_texture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphics Town Buildings (Exercise 4)</title>
      <link>/docs/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/6/</guid>
      <description>The pedagogical goals of this exercise are to give you practice defining shapes with meshes and adding textures to them.
In the coming weeks, you will make Graphics Town. To start, in this exercise you will make a few kinds of buildings to put into your town. Over the next weeks, you&amp;rsquo;ll make more stuff to go into the town.
For this assignment, you need to make at least two different kinds of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Car for Graphics Town (ex 5)</title>
      <link>/docs/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/7/</guid>
      <description>The pedagogical goals of this exercise are to give you practice defining shapes with meshes and adding textures to them.
In graphics town, you will need vehicles. A cars, trucks, trains, or maybe other things.
So in this page, please make one. It has to have wheels on the ground. But other than that, few restrictions - you can have a primitive (like a box or something) for the body. The vehicle must either have shape or texture to make it look like a car/truck/train.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>